Hello everyone and welcome
to English Pot, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and
we have another episode
in our series all about giving
presentations in English.
So this is show number eight for us.
That's right, we are getting
towards the end of the series.
On this occasion, on presentation series
number eight, we're going to continue with
Mr. Ford and try to handle a couple
of problems that keep coming up.
All right, so let's take
a listen to our dialogue
and we'll be back in a
moment to discuss it.
So as I mentioned
previously, the campaign
advertisement will focus
on those key elements
that every consumer
looks for in a quality laptop,
affordability, quality,
speed, and reliability.
We have pulled out all
the stops to produce a
product that really
rivals all our competitors.
Actually, just to illustrate my point,
let me give you an anecdote here.
I remember last year I was playing
golf with one of our key suppliers.
It was a lovely summer afternoon.
Anyway, I invited our
supplier for a game of
golf and wanted to get
his input on the new X420.
Actually, I often get together
with him for a good game of golf.
It really is a wonderful way to relax.
To be honest, I'm not that great at golf,
but I've improved in the last few years.
But the key to golf is practice, practice,
practice, sorry, I lost my thread.
What was I talking about again?
I think you were discussing the
campaign advertisement, Michael?
Yes, excuse me, I'm afraid
I got sidetracked there.
Yes, anyway, the campaign, well, or let me
see, is the projector working at Jonathan?
No, sorry, IT is still fixing it.
Okay, hmm, well, all the information
on the campaign is on the PowerPoint.
I haven't actually got my
notes with me, erm, let me see.
Mr. Ford, could you at least tell
us the schedule for the campaign?
When are the first
advertisements scheduled for?
That's a good question.
Unfortunately, I, er, don't
have that information on me.
I'll have to get back to you on that point.
Okay, Michael, the projector
is fixed, I think we're ready.
Thank goodness.
Okay, everyone, sorry for the delay.
So without further ado, the
new X420 Marketing Campaign.
Enjoy.
Oh, er, I'm terribly sorry.
This is not the advert.
This is my golfing holiday in Barbados.
I think I must have brought the wrong file.
Can we take five?
Come on, Mr. Ford.
All right, we're back
and Mr. Ford face a very
embarrassing moment here, erm, but
he also used a lot of interesting vocab.
Why don't we take a look at
that now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
At the beginning of
today's dialogue, we heard
a word that's very
interesting and anecdote.
What is an anecdote, Marco?
Right.
He started telling a story, and
that's basically an anecdote.
A life experience or a
story, something that
happened to you and you
want to share with people.
Right.
So an anecdote is a story.
So he was talking
about golfing with a
client and this is why, and
so this is called an anecdote.
He was telling a story about it.
After that, though, we realized
that he is a little bit distracted.
He says, "I'm afraid I
got sidetracked there.
" That's right.
So he's obviously talking
about the computer
and the marketing campaign and then he starts
talking about golf and how great it is.
So he says, "I got sidetracked.
" And that means that
you got distracted or you
started talking about something
that's not related to the topic.
So I really like to eat
hamburgers and I like
hamburgers with
cheese, actually, but wait.
That's all right.
Just got a little sidetracked there.
I think we should focus
on English right now.
That's right.
So it happens sometimes,
maybe you're even
talking to someone and something
is happening behind that person.
You get sidetracked and
you're not really paying attention.
That's right.
And after that, we realize that there's
still a problem with the projector and Mr.
Ford asks if it's working yet.
Jonathan, his assistant says,
"No, sorry, IT are still fixing it.
" All right, so this
acronym, IT, I think many of
you have heard it and it means
for information technology.
Okay, information
technology that has to do
with computers and so
when we have a technical
problem or a computer
problem, we usually call IT.
That's right.
So your company probably
has an IT department
or if you have as
Catherine said a problem
with your computer, you just
call IT to get them to fix it for you.
Exactly.
Another computer related
word comes up later where Mr.
Ford says that all of the information
about the campaign is on the PowerPoint.
That's right.
So PowerPoint.
This is a computer program that is
very well known for giving presentations.
So you probably use this if you
ever have to give a presentation.
That's right.
And PowerPoint is a part
of the Microsoft Office suite.
So you know the program
word or the program XSALB.
So PowerPoint helps you use your
computer to give a presentation.
So you often hear us
just talk about PowerPoint.
Can you help me with
this PowerPoint in English?
That's right.
Okay, so that's all the words we
have for you on language takeaway.
Why don't we listen to Mr. Ford again and
we'll be back soon with Fluency Builder.
So as I mentioned
previously, the campaign
advertisement will focus
on those key elements
that every consumer
looks for in a quality laptop,
affordability, quality,
speed, and reliability.
We have pulled out all
the stops to produce a
product that really
rivals all our competitors.
Actually, just to illustrate my point,
let me give you an anecdote here.
I remember last year I was playing
golf with one of our key suppliers.
It was a lovely summer afternoon.
Anyway, I invited our
supplier for a game of
golf and wanted to get
his input on the new X420.
Actually, I often get together
with him for a good game of golf.
It really is a wonderful way to relax.
To be honest, I'm not that great at golf,
but I've improved in the last few years.
But the key to golf is
practice, practice, practice.
Um, sorry, I've lost my thread.
What was I talking about again?
I think you were discussing the
campaign advertisement, Michael?
Yes, excuse me.
I'm afraid I got sidetracked there.
Yes, anyway, the campaign, well, or let me
see, is the projector working at Jonathan?
No, sorry.
IT is still fixing it.
Uh, okay, hmm, well, all the information
on the campaign is on the power point.
I haven't actually got my notes with me.
Um, let me see, uh...
Mr. Ford, could you at least tell
us the schedule for the campaign?
When are the first
advertisements scheduled for?
That's a good question.
Unfortunately, I, uh, don't
have that information on me.
I'll have to get back to you on that point.
Okay, Michael, the projector is fixed.
I think we're ready.
Thank goodness.
Okay, everyone, sorry for the delay.
So without further ado, the
new X420 marketing campaign.
Enjoy.
Oh, uh, I'm terribly sorry.
This is not the advert.
This is my golfing holiday in Barbados.
I think I must have brought the wrong file.
Can we take five?
Come on, Mr. Ford.
All right, so we've picked out a
lot of great phrases for you today.
Let's start with the first
one on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
At the very beginning,
Mr. Ford says we have
pulled out all the stops to
make a really great product.
That's right.
So the phrase used here
to pull out all the stops.
What does that mean?
Well, you don't have to think
about what it actually means.
We use this when we're trying
to say that we've done our best.
We have really gone as far
as we can, a hundred percent.
We're giving everything we can to
make this thing the best that it can be.
Okay.
So you've put a lot of effort and
resources into making something great.
You didn't hold back.
You didn't save any money.
You just went for it.
Okay.
Very good.
Now, when we were
talking about Mr.
Ford being distracted and he started
talking about golf, he said, Oh, I'm sorry.
I've lost my thread.
What was I talking about again?
All right.
That was interesting because the word thread
can mean something that you, it's like
a string that you used
to sew it clothes with.
But in this particular case, we're
talking about a thread of conversation.
And so that's basically the
topic that he's talking about.
Okay.
So when he said, I lost my thread, he makes
reference to the thread of conversation of
what he was talking about.
Right.
So he's talking about
golf, but he lost his thread.
So then he doesn't remember
what he was talking about.
Okay.
Very good.
So Ford actually faced a couple of
questions from the audience members.
One of them asked
about the schedule for the
campaign and he said, you know
what, I really don't have that information.
I will have to get back
to you on that point.
Well, this is a really
great way to answer a
question you don't
actually know how to answer.
In this case, Mr. Ford
doesn't have the
answer to this audience members
question like you said, Marka.
So he just says, I will have
to get back to you on that.
I will have to let you know later.
So it's a much better,
so it's much better to
say I will get back to you
instead of saying I don't know.
For example, if your
boss asks you, I don't
know, how were sales last
last year compared to this year?
And if you don't know, it's really not
recommendable to say, I don't know.
You don't want to say, I don't know.
It makes you sound like
you don't know anything.
And so in this case, you say, listen, I
really have to get back to you about that.
I want to check some numbers.
Right.
Very good.
Moving on to our next
phrase, when finally he
was going to present
the ad campaign, he said,
so without further ado, the
new 420 marketing campaign.
All right, this phrase
without further ado is
something that we
commonly hear in speeches
or more formal occasions,
but it's something
that we say when we want
to introduce something.
We say, we're not going
to talk about it anymore.
Let's just do it.
Let's just show you.
The word adu is
this, this is I think like
classic English, it's not really
common to hear anymore.
No, there is actually a very famous play by
Shakespeare called much adu about nothing.
And that means, you
know, that there's a
lot of talking and and a lot of problems
and a lot of drama about this one thing.
And so basically, when
we say the phrase without
further adu, we're
saying, you know, without
further talking, talking
about this anymore.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's a nice way to
say, okay, finally, we're
going to do this or finally,
we're going to see this.
And obviously, the video
was not the campaign.
It was his golfing holiday in Barbados.
So he asked someone if he could take five.
All right, this phrase
to take five is very,
very common in English
and it's just another
way to say, can we
take a five minute break?
So maybe you can
ask your teacher, excuse
me, can we take five
or something like that?
Yeah.
Because I'm, I need a glass of water.
Let's take five.
Right.
So that means let's have a short break.
Let's take a five minute
break, but it doesn't
always necessarily
have to be five minutes.
Now it can be seven minutes or 10
minutes, but take five means a short break.
Okay.
Very good.
So you don't say, can we
take 10 or can we take seven?
Now you usually just say take five.
Take five.
Okay.
All right.
So a lot of phrases
there, a lot of great stuff.
Let's review it one last time.
So as I mentioned
previously, the campaign
advertisement will focus
on those key elements
that every consumer
looks for in a quality laptop,
affordability, quality,
speed, and reliability.
We have pulled out all
the stops to produce a
product that really
rivals all our competitors.
Actually, just to illustrate my point,
let me give you an anecdote here.
I remember last year I was playing
golf with one of our key suppliers.
It was a lovely summer afternoon.
Anyway, I invited our
supplier for a game of
golf and wanted to get
his input on the new X420.
Actually, I often get together
with him for a good game of golf.
It really is a wonderful way to relax.
To be honest, I'm not that great at golf,
but I've improved in the last few years.
But the key to golf is
practice, practice, practice.
Um, sorry, I've lost my thread.
What was I talking about again?
I think you were discussing the
campaign advertisement, Michael?
Yes, excuse me.
I'm afraid I got sidetracked there.
Yes, anyway, the
campaign, well, or let me
see, is the projector
working yet, Jonathan?
No, sorry, IT is still fixing it.
Uh, okay, hmm, well, all the information
on the campaign is on the powerpoint.
I haven't actually got my notes with me,
um, let me see, uh, Mr. Ford, could you at
least tell us the schedule
for the campaign?
When are the first
advertisements scheduled for?
That's a good question.
Unfortunately, I, uh, don't
have that information on me.
I'll have to get back to you on that point.
Okay, Michael, the projector is fixed.
I think we're ready.
Thank goodness.
Okay, everyone, sorry for the delay.
So without further ado, the
new X420 marketing campaign.
Enjoy.
Oh, uh, I'm terribly sorry.
This is not the advert.
This is my golfing holiday in Barbados.
I think I must have brought the wrong file.
Can we take five?
Come on, Mr. Ford.
Okay, so we're coming towards
the end of our presentation series.
So be sure to listen to
us next week when we're
talking about presentation
series part nine.
And as you may know,
it ends up with part 10,
so then we'll start with a
new series very, very soon.
And, uh, I don't know if
you have any questions
or any suggestions about a
series, you can always contact us.
Yeah, please do let us
know what are the things
that you have a hard
time with when you're
studying English or other things
that are confusing or difficult.
We're happy to hear your suggestions
and we hope that we can help out.
Uh, that's about it for us today though.
So until next time.
Bye.